Guide to the Brooklyn playbills and programs collection BCMS.0041
Brooklyn Collection
- Brighton Beach Music Hall
  - Jubel, September 4, 1899 (Box 1)
    Performances by Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band (including "Jubel"); Edestus, equilibrist; The Blondells, stars of the Katzenjammer Kids; Pearl Andrews, mimic; Tovollo, ventriloquist; Ward and Curran, comedy excentriques. Programme changed weekly.
  - High-Class Vaudeville, July 23-29, 1900 (Box 1)
    Performances by Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band; Carrie Graham, The Original "Sis Hopkins"; Hooker & Davis, dancing specialty; McIntyre & Heath, in "The Georgia Minstrels"; 3-Livingstons-3, acrobats; Yorke & Adams, Hebrew Comedians, The American Vitagraph.
  - American Fantasia, July 1-8, 1900 (Box 1)
    Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band (including "American Fantasia"); Mr. & Mrs. Swickard, comedy duettists; Polk & Tresk, gymnasts; Miss Louise Gunning, singer; Stinson & Merton; Kiralfy Grand Ballet; John W. Ransone, impersonator; The American Vitagraph.
  - Soldiers' Dream, June 30-July 6, 1902 (Box 1)
    Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band (including "Soldiers' Dream"); Brighton Beach Orchestra; Three Marvelous Merrills, cyclists; Mayme Gehrue, dancer; James F. Dolan & Ida Lenharr, in a farce; The Talkative Miss Norton, storyteller; et al.
  - William Tell, July 14-20, 1902 (Box 1)
    Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band (including "William Tell"); Brighton Beach Orchestra; Batty's Bears; The Andalusians, native songs of Spain; Carter De Haven Trio, variety skits; Jordan & Welch, "The Two Hebrews"; Rosa Naynon, bird trainer; McIntyre & Heath.
  - Semiramidi, July 28-August 3, 1902 (Box 1)
    Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band (including "Semiramidi"); Brighton Beach Orchestra; 3-Great Nevaros-3, acrobats; Zelma Rawlston, male impersonator; Harry Watson & Co, in a farce; La Belle Blanche, imitations; Williams & Walker, songs; Herbert's Dog Circus.
  - Florodora, August 4-10, 1902 (Box 1)
    Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band (including "Florodora"); Brighton Beach Orchestra; Orville & Frank, acrobats; Ida Russell, comedianne; The Great Colombino, in a farce; Jehan Bedini & Arthur, jugglers; Monroe & Wesley, dancer and comedian; Williams & Walker.
  - Tannhauser, August 11-18, 1902 (Box 1)
    Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band (inc."Tannhauser"); Brighton Beach Orchestra; Hale & Francis, novelty; Crane Bro. & Belmont, minstrels; Ray L. Royce, monologue; NY Comedy Four, in a farce; Vira Rial, chanteur; Fratelli Riccobono's Marvelous Educated Horses.
  - Lustspiel, Septemer 1-7, 1902 (Box 1)
    Slafer's Brooklyn Marine Band (inc."Lustspiel"); Drawee, juggler; Clara Francis, singer; The Salvaggis, dancers; George Fuller Golden, monologue; The McWatters-Tyson Co; Sisters Hawthorne, in an operetta; J. Warren Keane, card tricks; et al.
  - Our Banner, July 6-12, 1903 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orchestra (inc."Our Banner"); The Great Alexius; Gebest Sisters; Gillett's Musical Dogs; James Richard Glenroy; Roatina & Stevens; McIntyre & Heath; "A Journey to Luna" by the American Vitagraph.
  - Hail to the Nation, July 20-26, 1903 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orchestra (inc."Hail to the Nation"); Marguerite & Hanley; Hafford & Worth; Charles H. Bradsaw & Co; Sisters Meredith; George Evans; Colby & Way; "Jack and the Beanstalk" by the American Vitagraph.
  - Jimmie, July 27-August 2, 1903 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orchestra (inc. "Jimmie"); Edestus, equilibrist; West & Van Siclen, in a musical extravaganza; Fleury Trio, dancers; Loney Haskell; Imro Fox, comic; Shean & Warren; "Life of a Gamester" by the American Vitagraph.
  - The Jewel of Asia, August 17-23, 1903 (Box 1)
    L. Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orch. (inc. "The Jewel of Asia"); The Two Roses; Zazell & Vernon; Aurie Dagwell; Jean Marcel's Living Art Studies & Bas Reliefs; Mortons; Golman's Dogs and Cats; "Sleeping Beauty and the Beast" by American Vitagraph.
  - King Dodo, August 31-September 6, 1903 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orchestra (inc. "King Dodo"), La Petit Mignon, Vera King, Reno & Richards, Marie Dressler, Press Eldridge, Canfield & Carlton, Milani Trio, Paul Lamar, "Reliance-Shamrock Yacht Races" by American Vitagraph.
  - The Monarch, June 11-19, 1904 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orchestra (inc. "The Monarch"), The De Onzo Bros., Daisy Dumont, Emmet Devoy & Co., Les 3 Dumonds, The Wilton Bros, Walter C. Kelly, Winscherman's, "Japan and Russian War" by American Vitagraph.
  - Swanee River, June 20-26, 1904 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orchestra (inc. "Swanee River"), Zimmer, Eddie Girard & Jessie Gardner, Jessie Bradbury, Mr. Charles Hawtrey & Co., Fisher & Carroll, Stein-Eretto Family, "The St. Louis Fair" by American Vitagraph.
  - Sergeant Kitty, June 27-July 3, 1904 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orch. (inc. "Sergeant Kitty"), Belleclaie Bros., Geo. C. Boniface Jr. & Bertha Waltzinger, Barry & Halvers, Miss Jessie Millward, Smith & Campbell, Ed. F. Reynard and pictures by American Vitagraph.
  - Winsome Winnie [selections], July 4-10, 1904 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orchestra (inc. "Winsome Winnie"), Cartmell & Harris, Bedini & Arthur, Bert Howard & Leona Bland, Rhoada Bernard, Dan McAvoy, The Misses Delmore, Simon & Gardner and pictures by American Vitagraph.
  - Babette [selections], July 11-17, 1904 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orchestra (inc. "Babette"), M'lle Olive, Ethel Robinson, Carter De Haven's Miniature Production, Cliff Gordon, Edna Wallace Hopper, Empire City Quartette, Harding & Ah Sid, "The Welcher" by American Vitagraph.
  - Two Roses, July 18-24, 1904 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orch., "Two Roses", M'lle Amoros, Lawrence Crane, Leonard Grover Jr & Co., Hoey & Lee, Geo. Primrose & The Foley Boys, Quaker City Quartette, Tony Wilson & Heloise, "Life of Marie Antoinette" by American Vitagraph.
  - The Good Old Summer Time, July 25-31, 1904 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orch.("The Good Old Summer Time"), Alice Shaw, Countess Mignon d'Alencon, J. Warren Keane, Ford & Gehrue, Delmore & Lee, George Evans, Capt. Webb's Seals and Sea Lions and the American Vitagraph.
  - The Musical Gymnasium, August 15-21, 1904 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orch.; West & Van Siclen in "The Musical Gymnasium"; Miss Norton & Paul Nicholson; Hathaway & Walton; Hickey & Nelson; Elita Proctor Otis; Henry Lee; George Wilson; Ten Brooke, Lambert & Co; Marzella.
  - The Sho-Gun, August 22-28, 1904 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orch. (inc. "The Sho-Gun"); Gebest Sisters; Kelly & Ashby; Vera King; Henry E. Dixey; Edna Aug; Rose Stahl & Co.; Sydney Grant; Herbert's Performing Dogs; "Saturday Shopping" by American Vitagraph.
  - Blue Bell, August 29-September 4, 1904 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orch. (inc. "Blue Bell"); Thomas Nast, Jr.; Wright Huntington & Co.; Violet Dale; Tom Lewis & Sam J. Ryan; Pat Rooney & Marion Bent; Helen Bertram; et al. "Saturday Shopping" by American Vitagraph.
  - Gartenfest, September 5-11, 1904 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis Reinhard's Famous Orpheum Theatre Orch. (inc. "Gartenfest"); Adimini & Tayler; Carl Dammann Troupe; Mark Sullivan; The Great Buckner; Elizabeth Murray; Agnes Mahr; Rapoli; et al. The American Vitagraph.
  - Love's Lottery, June 10-18, 1905 (Box 1)
    Performances by The Amphion Theatre Orch., directed by Carl Reckewell, (inc. "Love's Lottery"); Three La Maze Bros.; Charlotte Ravenscroft; The Great Rapoli; Bissert & Scott; Wilfred Clarke; Harrigan; Belle Hathaway; Motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - Babes in Toyland, June 19-25, 1905 (Box 1)
    Performances by The Amphion Theatre Orch., directed by Carl Reckewell, (inc. "Babes in Toyland"); Niblo & Reilly; Frank H. White & Lew Simmons; Miss May Robson & Co.; Lillian Tyce & Irene Jermon; Sam Elton; et al. Motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - The Isle of Spice [selection], July 3-9, 1905 (Box 1)
    Performances by The Amphion Theatre Orch., directed by Carl Reckewell, (inc. "The Isle of Spice"); Albert Kartelli; M'lle Chester's Statue Dog; Johnson & Wells; Arthur Byron; Louis Gunning; Ward & Curran; et al. Motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - Babette [selection], July 10-16, 1905 (Box 1)
    Performances by The Amphion Theatre Orch., directed by Carl Reckewell, (inc. "Babette"); Collins & Hawley; Laura Millard; Herbert Lloyd; The Juggling McBanns; Olive May & J.W. Albaugh, Jr.; Frank Bush; et al. Motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - The Hippodrome, July 17-23, 1905 (Box 1)
    Performances by The Amphion Theatre Orch., directed by Carl Reckewell, (inc. "The Hippodrome"); Brandow & Wiley; Theodore Babcock; Jos. Morris; Leonard Grover, Jr.; Edna Aug; Col. Gaston Bordeverry; Quigley Bros.; et al. Motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - Grand Fantasia, August 21-27, 1905 (Box 1)
    Performances by The Amphion Theatre Orch., directed by Carl Reckewell, (inc. "Grand Fantasia"); Gollando; Eddie Gray; Sisters Herzog Camaras; Clifford & Burke; Henry Miller; The Musical Tobins; Hayes & Healey; et al. Motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - A Society Circus [selection], July 2-8, 1906 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis C. A. Reinhard's Orchestra, (inc. "A Society Circus"); 3 Westons; Kennedy & Rooney; Taylor Holmes; Robt. Hilliard; Mayme Remmington; Hawthorne & Burt; Mazuz & Mazet. Motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - Vesta Victoria's Songs, July 9-15, 1906 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis C. A. Reinhard's Orchestra, (inc. "Vesta Victoria's Songs"); Herbert Brooks; Fred Watson & The Morrisey Sisters; Eleanor Henry; Walter Jones & Mabel Hite; Nate M. Wills; Ward & Curran; The Juggling Bannans. Kinetograph.
  - The Governor's Son [selection], July 30-August 5, 1906 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis C. A. Reinhard's Orchestra, (inc. "The Governor's Son"); Pongo & Leon; Billy Clifford; Henri French; The Sisters Meredith; Arthur Dunn; Edwin Stevens; Empire City Quartette; Herbert's Dogs. Kinetograph.
  - The Vanderbilt Cup [selection], August 27-September 2, 1906 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis C. A. Reinhard's Orchestra, (inc. "The Vanderbilt Cup"); Marseilles; Macy & Hall; Mathews & Ashley; Ned Nye; Prof. Hermann; The Elinore Sisters; The Four Rianos; Motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - Neptune's Daughter, June 15, 1907 (Box 1)
    Performances by Louis C. A. Reinhard's Orchestra, (inc. "Neptune's Daughter"); Davis & Walker; Mme. Sophie Akounine; Howard & North; The Zingari Operatic Troupe; Raymond Finley & Lottie Burke; George Evans; Cornella & Eddie; and the Kinetograph.
  - The Tattooed Man, June 24, 1907 (Box 1)
    Louis C. A. Reinhard's Orchestra, (inc. "The Tattooed Man"); Rennier & Gaudier; Martine & Maxmillian; Les 3 Dumonds; "The Governor's Son," a farce; Jewell's Wonderful Electric Manikins; Empire Comedy 4; Morris & Morris; motion pictures by Kinetograph.
  - The Yankee Prince, July 6, 1908 (Box 1)
    Selection from "The Yankee Prince"; Felix, cartoonist; Tom Jack Trio; Swor Bros.; The De Haven Sextette; The Avon Comedy 4; Julie Ring & Co.; Six American Dancers; Nat M. Wills; The Jossetti Troupe; views by Vitagraph.
  - Shapiro's Song Successes, August 22, 1910 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Orchestra performs medley, "Shapiro's Song Successes"; Kessler & Lee; Corinne Frances; The Huntings; Wilson & Pearson; "Models of Jardin Paris,"; Edmund Stanley & Co.; Jack Wilson; Charmion; The American Vitagraph.
  - Song Review, July 17, 1911 (Box 1)
    Louis Reinhard's Renowned Rythmists performs medley, "Song Review"; Stewart & Donohue; Lucy Weston; Bert Leslie; Pedersen Bros.; Mike Bernard & Willie Weston; McIntyre & Heath; Mabelle Fonda Troupe.
  - The Birth Of A Nation, July 24, 1915 (Box 1)
    Screening of the film by D. W. Griffith, "The Birth Of A Nation," a drama in Two Acts. Founded on Thomas Dixon's story, "The Clansman." Starring Henry Walthall, Miriam Cooper, Mae Marsh, Ralph Lewis, Lillian Gish, et al.
- Brighton Theatre
  - The Respectful Prostitute, August 8, 1950 (Box 1)
    "The Respectful Prostitute" by Jean-Paul Sartre, New Stages Inc. Production. With Elizabeth Dillon, Ken Renard, et al.Together With "Native Son," Adapted by Susan Laurence and Loy Nilson from the play by Paul Green and Richard Wright.
  - The Red Soldier, [post-1946] (Box 1)
    Oscar Green presents "The Red Soldier." Musical comedy in 2 Acts & 8 Scenes by Louis Freiman. Music by Maurice Rauch, lyrics by Louis Markowitz, staged by Paul Burstein, settings by Saltzman Bros., costumes by Nathan Geiptman. With Bennie Seidman, et al.
- Broadway Theatre (New)
  - The Bishop Murder Case, May 18, 1930 (Box 1)
    "The Bishop Murder Case" with Basil Rathbone, et al. Geo. O'Brien in "Lone Star Ranger." "The River Woman" with Lionel Barrymore, Rex Lease in "Troopers Three." "Twin Beds" with Jack Mulhall, et al. Marion Davies in "Marianne." Also Vitaphone Act.
- Broadway Theatre (Teller's)
  - The Heir to the Hoorah, January 15, 1906 (Box 1)
    The Kirke La Shelle Production of "The Heir To The Hoorah," an American Comedy by Paul Amstrong, with Guy Bates Post, Harry Rich, Florence Coventry, T. Tamamoto, Nora O'Brien, et al.
  - The College Widow, February 26, 1906 (Box 1)
    "The College Widow" by George Ade, Staged by George Marion, General Stage Director for Mr. Savage, American Comedy, with Thomas Meighar, George E. Bryan, Edwin Holt, et al.
  - Three Twins, September 6, 1909 (Box 1)
    Jos. M. Gaites introduces the "Three Twins" by Charles Dickson. Adapted from R. Pacheco's farce, "Incog." Lyrics by O.A.Hauerbach, Music by Karl Hoschna. Staged by Gus Sohlke. W.H. Oviatt, General Manager. With William Meehan, Jos. Allen, et al.
  - Fine Feathers, January 26, 1914 (Box 1)
    H. H. Frazee presents "Fine Feathers." A Play of Today, in Four Acts, by Eugene Walter. With with Rose Coghlan, Florence Rockwell, Robert Edeson, Max Figman, Wilton Lackaye, et al. Play produced by author.
  - The Slim Princess, September 4, 1911 (Box 1)
    Charles Dillingham presents "The Slim Princess," a comic opera in Three Acts. Book & lyrics by Henry Blossom, music by Leslie Stuart. Adapted from the story by George Ade. Staged by Austen Hurgon. With Elsie Janis, Joseph Cawthorn, Eugene Revere, et al.
- Brooklyn (Werba's)
  - Boy Meets Girl, September 27, 1937 (Box 1)
    "Boy Meets Girl" a Comedy by Bella and Samuel Spewack. Setting by Arne Lundborg. Staged by Donald Oliver. With Howard Ferguson, Byron Shores, Warren Ashe, Juan Varro, et al. Under the personal direction of Louis F. Werba.
- Brooklyn Academy of Music
  - Thursby and Ole Bull, April 26, 1880 (Box 1)
    Maurice Strakosch and David Taylor announce the joint appearance of Miss Thursby and Ole Bull in One Grand Concert. The following artists will also appear: Emily Winant, Anna Bock, Mme. Chatterton-Bohrer, Sig. Brignoli, Sig. Ferranti & Mons. Fischer.
  - Single Life, April 25, 1883 (Box 1)
    J.B. Buckstone's Comedy in 4 Acts. The Kemble souvenir programme, 1882-83.
  - The Amaranth, January 13, 1886 (Box 1)
  - Musicale, November 8, 1886 (Box 1)
    Performances by Dudley Buck Quartette, New York Philharmonic Club, Francis Fisher Powers, Eugene Weiner, and "Miss MacCollum." Accompanist, Mr. John Hyatt Brewer.
  - Amphion Private Concert, December 14, 1886 (Box 1)
    C. Mortimer Wiske, Musical Director; Frank J. Mulligan, Accompanist. Soloists: Mme. Blanche Stone Barton, soprano; James Blamphin, Harpist. Amphion Orchestra and Chorus.
  - Faust, December 28, 1886 (Box 1)
    American Opera Programme. Grand Opera, in Five Acts, by Gounod. William Hock, Stage Director. Ballet arranged by Prof. Mamert Bibeyran. Kermes, Walpurgis Night, and Grand Bacchanale Ballet. Starring Charles Bassett, William Ludwig, Alonzo Stoddard, et al.
  - Aida, December 29, 1886 (Box 1)
    American Opera Programme. Grand Opera, in Four Acts, by Verdi. William Hock, Stage Director. Ballet arranged by Prof. Mamert Bibeyran. Starring William H. Hamilton, Cornelia Van Zanten, Madame Fursch-Madi, William Candidus, Myron W. Whitney, et al.
  - Galatea, December 30, 1886 (Box 1)
    American Opera. In One Act by Victor Masse. First Grand Ballet Night. Follwed by Grand Spectacular Ballet arranged to the Bal Costume. Ballet music by Rubinstein. Ballet arranged by Prof. Mamert Bibeyran. With Laura Moore, Jessie Bartlett Davis, et al.
  - Lohengrin, December 31, 1886 (Box 1)
    American Opera Programme. Grand Opera in Three Acts by Richard Wagner. Beginning at a quarter before eight. William Hock, Stage Director. The Cast: Myron W. Whitney, William Candidus, Bertha Pierson, William Ludwig, William Merton, Cornelia Van Zanten.
  - The Flying Dutchman, January 1, 1887 (Box 1)
    American Opera Programme. Grand Opera in Three Acts by Richard Wagner. Beginning at a quarter before eight. William Hock, Stage Director. The Cast: William Ludwig, Emma Juch, Myron W. Whitney, Charles Bassett, Mathilde Phillipps, William H. Fessenden.
  - The Marriage of Jeannette; Sylvia, January 1, [1887] (Box 1)
    "The Marriage of Jeanette," an Opera in One Act by Victor Masse. Cast: Pauline L'Allemand, John E. Brand, et al. Followed by "Sylvia,"a Ballet in Two Acts and Four Tableaux by Leo Delibes. The Cast: Theodora De Gillert, Mlle. Pessione, et al. Dated via coverage in the Brooklyn Daily Eagle.
  - Ovide Musin's Concert, January 25, 1887 (Box 1)
    With the assistance of Mme. Zelia Trebelli, Contralto. Herr Anton Seidl (by permission of E.C. Stanton, esq.) and his Grand Orchestra from the Metropolitan Opera House, New York.
  - Martha, March 3, [1887] (Box 1)
    American Opera Programme. An Opera in Four Acts by F. von Flotow. First performance in Brooklyn by the National Opera Company of "Martha." William Hock, Stage Director. The Cast: Pauline L'allemand, Jessie Bartlett Davis, William Hamilton, et al. Dated via coverage in the Brooklyn Daily Eagle.
  - The Flying Dutchman, March 17, [1887] (Box 1)
    American Opera Programme. Grand Opera in English. Romantic Opera in Three Acts by R Wagner. William Hock, Stage Director. The Cast: William Ludwig, Bertha Pierson, Myron W. Whitney, Charles Bassett, Mathilde Phillipps and William H. Fessenden, et al. Dated via coverage in the Brooklyn Daily Eagle.
  - Lakmé, March 24, [1887] (Box 1)
    American Opera Programme. Opera in Three Acts by Leo Delibes. Ballet composed by Mamert Bibeyran. William Hock, Stage Director. The Cast: Pauline Lállemand, Alonzo E. Stoddard, Charles Bassett, et al. Grand Ballet of the Bayaderes. Music by Leo Delibes. Dated via coverage in the Brooklyn Daily Eagle.
  - Brooklyn Choral Society, May 31, 1887 (Box 1)
    Second Private Concert. J. C. Dempsey, Conductor. Assisted by Chevalier B. de Salas. Soloists: Lillian Blauvelt, Edith M. Dutcher, Wilford S. Watters, C. C. Ferguson. Accompanists: Arnold W. Meyer, F. Toledo and selected artists.
  - Josef Hofmann, December 9, 1887 (Box 1)
    Sixth appearance in America of Josef Hofmann under the personal direction of Henry E. Abbey. Adolph Neuendorff, conductor. Also appearing: Nettie Carpenter, Helene Hastreiter, Sig. De Anna, Mme. Sacconi. Music include pieces by Weber, Beethoven, et al.
  - Boston Symphony Society, December 12, 1887 (Box 1)
    Boston Symphony Society. William Gericke, Conductor. Soloist for First Concert: Gertrude Edmands. Selections by Weber, Bruch, Bach, Schubert, Greig, Beethoven.
  - Damrosch Symphony Society of Brooklyn, January 31, 1888 (Box 1)
    Soloists for Third Concert: Lilli Lehmann (from the Metropolitan Opera House), Alexander Lambert. Selections by Beethoven, Rubinstein, Brahms, Greig, Ambroise Thomas, Litolff, Liszt.
  - Brooklyn Choral Society, February 27, 1889 (Box 1)
    Second private concert. C. Mortimer Wiske, Musical Director. Miss Grace A. Povey, Accompanist. Soloists G. del Punete, Henry D. Clark, Charles S. Phillips, and Frederic Reddall. Also included New York Philharmonic Club.
  - H. M. S. Pinafore, February 13, 1890 (Box 1)
    Amateur Opera Association of Brooklyn presents Gilbert & Sullivan's Nautical Comic Opera, in Two Acts. Cast: M. Berdu, Jr.; Thomas T. Barry; A. G. Nickolds; J. W. Macy, et al. Will W. Thomas, Musical Director, H. F. Dixie, Stage Manager.
  - The Amaranth, March 12, 1890 (Box 1)
    The Amaranth Dramatic Society. "Caprice," a domestic play in four acts, produced by the courtesy of Miss Minnie Maddern. Music by the 23rd Regiment Band. Alfred D. Fohs, Director.
  - The Amaranth, March 16, 1892 (Box 1)
    Gretchen by W.S. Gilbert. Cast includes Alfred Young, Frederick Bowne, and H.C. Edwards. Music by 23rd Regiment Band. Alfred D. Fohs, Director.
  - Complimentary Concert Tended to Mr. Oscar J. Murray, April 29, 1893 (Box 1)
    Performers include Emma C. Thursby, Alice Mandelick, Paul Tidden, Raphael Diaz Albertine, H.M. Heidelberg, the DeKoven Quartette, and Harry Rowe Shelley.
  - The Theosophist, March 1-3, 1894 (Box 1)
    Polytechnic Dramatic Association, fourth season. First production of the three act musical extravaganza The Theosophist.
  - Cupid and Psyche, 1895 (Box 1)
    "Cupid and Psyche," an original three act musical burlesque. Produced under the direction of Henry Gaines Hawn. Polytechnic Dramatic Association season 1895.
  - L'Aiglon and La Dame Aux Camelias, April 5-6, 1901 (Box 1)
    Program of the engagement of Mme. Sarah Bernhardt and M. Coquelin. Management Oscar J. Murray.
  - The Bulletin of The Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, October 10, 1908 (Box 1)
    Bulletin published weekly containing information for events to be held at the Brooklyn Academy of Music. Events include: The David Bispham Song Recital, The Opening 'Cello and Piano Recital, The Mme. Chaminade Concert, Dr. John C. Bowker Lectures, et al.
  - The Little Princess, March 20, 1909 (Box 1)
    The Educational Theatre for Children and Young People presents The Little Princess. A three-act drama by Frances Hodgson Burnett.
  - The Heart and the Hand, March 19, 1913 (Box 1)
    Joint address by Helen Keller and her teacher Mrs. John Macy (Anne M. Sullivan). Subject: The Heart and the Hand or The Right Use of Our Senses. Lecture Platform appearance.
  - Boys High School Commencement, June 24, 1926 (Box 1)
    Commencement Exercises of the Class of 1926, Boys High School.
  - Rip Van Winkle, October 14, 1933 (Box 1)
    Clare Tree Major presents The Children's Theatre of New York in a Series of Six Saturday Afternoon Plays for Children. "Rip Van Winkle" based on Washington Irving's Story. Cast: Eugenia Rawles, Madeline Fales, Wesley B. Whitehouse, et al.
  - Boys High School Commencement, June 28, 1939 (Box 1)
    Commencement Exercises of the Class of 1939, Boys High School.
  - Don Juan in Hell, October 25, 1951 (Box 1)
    "Don Juan in Hell" by Bernard Shaw. Directed by Charles Laughton. Starring Charles Boyer, Charles Laughton, Cedric Hardwicke, and Agnes Moorehead.
  - Vladimir Horowitz, November 11, 1952 (Box 1)
    Vladimir Horowitz, pianist. First in the major concert series. Analytical notes by Olin Downes.
  - The Royal Danish Ballet, October 28, 1956 (Box 1)
    Columbia Artists Management in association with Howard Lanin Management presents the Royal Danish Ballet. Ballet master Frank Schaufuss. Solo dancers include Mona Vangsaa, Borge Ralov, Kirsten Ralov, Svend Erik Jensen, Margarethe Schanne, Niels Bjorn Larsen et al.
  - National Ballet of Canada, March 30, 1957 (Box 1)
    Celia Franca, David Adams, Lois Smith et al. Orchestra conductor George Crum. Concert master and assistant conductor Charles Dobias. Includes newspaper clipping about the ballet dancers wearing warmup socks in the colors of their favorite hockey teams.
  - Renata Tebaldi, April 9, 1957 (Box 1)